Mr Thoma, you are
Sales Engineer for Voice Alarm Systems
at Siemens for Switzerland.
What would a layman make of your job title?
Security in a public building
is a big aspect.
In a restaurant
like the one here in Leon's Loft
We have a voice alert.
People are given guidance by loudspeakers,
and in the event of an incident
they can simply leave the building.
What kind of events can occur to enable an
evacuation?
The following events can occur,
such as a bomb alarm, fire alarm,
building alarm, or environmental alarm.
There are a lot of possibilities.
What needs to be taken into account when
evacuating buildings in general?
The important thing is to reach out and
reassure people,
so that people will follow the instructions
given by the speakers.
This way no major complications can
arise.
What is the role of voice evacuation
during evacuations ?
Voice evacuation, as opposed to
other siren systems,
is there to guide people.
In the event of an incident, they can now
rescue themselves relatively quickly
without causing any major damage.
Which products from your range
have you installed here in
Leon's Loft restaurant?
Here in Leons Loft we have installed our
Nivogo amplifiers,
two 250 watt amplifiers.
In addition, we have installed large
speakers and regulators,
i.e. volume controls.
This was very important to the customer
as he demanded increased quality.
What products have you
installed in The Circle?
We installed the Novigo system
in The Circle.
We have installed Siemens speakers
for the basic set-up
and for the tenant set-up we have
installed combined branded speakers.
What are the functions of the brand
loudspeakers?
The branded speakers perform two
functions -
better intelligibility and
voice quality
and also background music.
What was special about this 'The
Circle' project for you personally?
The size of the project.
We have interconnected around 80 Novigo
central units here,
that is, we can stream streaming services
and radio stations or radio programmes
in the network
and each tenant has the opportunity
to choose their own programme here.
What advantages do your products offer
over those of your competitors?
Our products, such as the control panels
and the controls
are easily networkable with
normal internet cables.
What challenges did you have to overcome
here in The Circle
and how did you solve them, Mr. Thoma?
Yes, the size was a big challenge,
of course,
as was the delivery of the products.
We could only have our products delivered
here at a certain time slot.
In addition, there were constant changes
to the floor plan or rents.
It wasn't all that simple.
But we are very proud of our employees
who have done a fantastic job here.